《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
他是谁
Who's that?
我是鲍勃·柯克兰  国土安全局的
Bob Kirkland, Homeland Security.
-我认识你吗  -不  但我认识你
- Do I know you? - No, but I know you.
全部都拿回来
Get me everything.
简把很多关于血腥约翰的线索都关联到了一起
Jane made a lot of Red John connections here.
很好
This is good.
为什么这还扯上了国土安全问题
Why is this a homeland security issue?
这里面的内情复杂
It's complicated.
我是里斯本探员  这位是简  加调局的
Agent Lisbon, Jane, CBI.
抱歉  只有联调局的人能进
Sorry, F.B.I. personnel only.
我们也不想来
Uh, we don't want to be here, either,
是别人邀请我们来的
but we were invited.
麻烦你告诉里德·史密斯探员
Uh, could you tell Agent Reede Smith
我们应约到了
that we're here as requested?
你认为史密斯意图何在
What do you think Smith wants?
我不知道  你怎么看
I don't know. What do you think?
每次要见血腥约翰案的疑犯
Every time we go to see one of these Red John suspects,
我都会很急躁
I get edgy.
是吗  看不出来
Really? Can't tell.
真的吗
Really?
简  里斯本  多谢前来
Jane, Lisbon. Thanks for coming.
谁愿意错过这个呢
Miss this? Who could say no?
我们能帮些什么  史密斯探员
How can we be of help, Agent Smith?
我们发现一具尸体
We caught a body.
我感觉你们会有兴趣
I thought it might interest you.
何出此言呢
And why would you say that?
你看了就知道了
You tell me.
他是本杰明·马克思
This is Benjamin Marx.
就是你活埋的那个人
The guy you buried alive.
出自第四季 第二十三集
恕我纠正一下
Excuse me.
是我活埋的那个杀人凶手
The killer I buried alive.
而且我最后放他出来了
And I did let him out-- eventually.
算你眼力准  尸体很难辨认
Not bad. That's a tough I.D.,
大部分脸都烧毁了
considering most of his face is burnt off.
你觉得他身上发生了什么事
What do you think happened to him?
你是联调局探员
You're the F.B.I.
你肯定已经知道了吧
I-I'm sure you have the answers already.
好吧
Okay.
那你说说我都发现了什么
Tell me what I've come up with.
首先  你肯定注意到了
Well, the first thing you'd notice
他被刑讯逼供了
is that he was tortured--
被人用火烧  还用别的什么凶器
with fire and whatever it is people use
砍下了他的手指
to cut someone's thumbs off.
那我认为凶手是想逼他说出什么呢
And what do I think he was tortured for?
你肯定认为凶手是为了获得施虐的快感
Well, your guess would be sadistic pleasure,
但你错了
but you'd be wrong.
凶手折磨他  更有可能是为了获取信息
More likely he was tortured for information--
他不知道的信息
Information that he didn't have.
你怎么知道他不知道
How do you know he didn't have it?
因为他如果知道的话
Because if he had it,
那个凶手只要烧掉他的半边脸他就招了
the killer would only have had to burn off half his face.
我还有其他什么想法没
What else do I think?
刑讯逼供需要时间
Well, whoever did the torturing took their time,
所以你会想到他们选用了一个僻静的地方
so you would reason that they had somewhere private to do it.
没错
Right.
我相信你看到了
And I'm sure you saw
死者的腿上有点黏糊糊的东西
the, uh, sticky stuff on the leg of the victim,
可能已经送去化验了
probably sent it off to the lab.
等三天后化验结果出来
And in three days they'll tell you
他们会告诉你那是松树树汁  那就说得通了
that it's pine sap, which makes sense,
因为他的鞋底嵌进了一根
Because there's a broken pine needle
断裂的松针
wedged into the sole of his shoe.
对  我看到了
Yeah, I see.
所以最终你会得出结论
Eventually you'd come to the conclusion
他是被人囚禁在某个树林里
that he was kept in the woods someplace
然后被杀害弃尸至此的
before he was killed and dumped here.
棒极了
Nice.
那为何要叫我们来这里  史密斯探员
Uh, why are we here, Agent Smith?
马克思受审期间被保释
Marx was out on bail while he stood trial.
事态对他也蛮有利的
Things were looking good for him, too.
你刑讯逼供让他认罪
I mean, you tortured him into a confession,
请有个好点的律师
so a little good lawyering,
再加上一点运气  他就没事了
a little luck, and he could walk.
那样就你就不好受了吧  简
Bet that really chapped your hide, huh, Jane?
一点没有
Not at all.
这就是联调局能得出的最好结论了吗
That's the best theory the F.B.I. can come up with?
你们认为是简杀了本杰明·马克思还烧掉了他的脸
That Jane killed Benjamin Marx and burned his face off?
我们得考虑所有可能性
We're exploring every angle.
他是其中一个
He's an angle.
如果我想杀掉本杰明·马克思
Listen. If I wanted to kill Benjamin Marx,
上次就动手了
I would have done it the first time.
他是专骗孤儿寡母钱的反社会分子
He was a sociopath that stole from widows and orphans,
他是罪有应得
and he got what he deserved.
但我没杀他
But I didn't do it.
等着看吧
We'll see.
好啊
Yes, we will.
多谢前来
Thanks for coming.
-怎么回事  简  -没事
- What's going on, Jane? - Nothing.
-告诉我  -我说了没事
- Tell me. - I said it's nothing.
你从来不会没事
It's never nothing with you.
你认为史密斯是血腥约翰吗
Do you think Smith is Red John?
有可能
Possibly.
如果他不是血腥约翰  那他就是个蠢货
Well, if he isn't Red John, he's an idiot
居然认为你跟马克思的死有关
for thinking you could have anything to do with Marx's death.
他也不是完全错了
He's not completely wrong.
当然  我没有杀本杰明·马克思
I mean, I-I didn't kill Benjamin Marx,
但是我可能间接害他被杀了
but I might have gotten him killed.
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：灰灰是菇凉  丁丁  王小麦  Michael  那时花开
■
超感警探
第六季
第四集
■
时间轴：兜兜兜爹  Sagelibra   校对：灰灰是菇凉
第六季
第四集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   精校&总监：灰灰是菇凉
好了  不准有任何隐瞒  快说
Okay, no more secrets. Spill it now.
我在分析血腥约翰案名单的时候很在意保密问题
I was concerned with security when I was working my list of Red John suspects.
你都保密到走火入魔了
Obsessively secretive.
随你怎么说
Yeah, well, you say "tomato,"
但是我知道有人想要我的信息
but I knew there were people that needed that information.
所以我就往板子上写上了
So I planted what you would call
你说的那种"错误信息"
misinformation on my crime board.
看到你的案件分析板的人
So whoever saw your crime board
就得到了血腥约翰案的七名疑犯名单
got the list of the seven Red John suspects.
但那是错的疑犯名单
But they would be the wrong suspects.
正是如此  而且起效了
Exactly. And it worked.
有人闯进了我的办公室
Someone broke into my office.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
我设了个小陷阱  牙签被人弄断了
Well, I set a trap, and it was sprung.
现在那个人手上有那份名单
Now this person has a fake list of Red John suspects,
而本杰明·马克思在那份名单上
and Benjamin Marx was on that list.
这么说有人在拷问和谋杀那些
So somebody is torturing and killing
你的假名单上的人
the people on your fake list.
没必要说得那么绝对
Whoa, whoa. N-not necessarily.
有人拷问并谋杀了我名单上的一个人
Someone tortured and killed one person from my list.
但从理论上讲  他的死可能出于任何原因
But theoretically, his death could be about anything.
他可不是个好人
He wasn't a nice man.
我反复在思考这件事想要理解
I am trying to wrap my mind around this.
你将七个无辜的人的生命置于危险之中
You put the lives of seven innocent people in danger.
不  他们没一个人是无辜的
No. None of them are innocent.
马克思诈骗了成千上百的人
Marx defrauded hundreds of people...
他为了掩盖这事  残忍杀害了一个人
Then he brutally murdered someone to cover it up.
我向你保证  里斯本
I assure you, Lisbon...
名单上的所有人都是恶人
All of these men are very bad.
只不过他们碰巧不是血腥约翰罢了
They just don't happen to be Red John.
你认为会是真的血腥约翰闯入这里
Do you think the real Red John could have broken in here
杀了马克思吗
and killed Marx?
除了我们  血腥约翰是唯一一个
Well, Red John is the only person besides us
知道真的疑犯名单的人
that knows the real list of suspects,
因此他也是唯一一个没有动机做此事的人
so he is the only person that has no motive to do this.
那闯进来的是谁
Then who broke in here?
我不知道
I don't know.
是一个便于进出这里  有很多手段与权力的人
Someone with easy access, a lot of resources and power.
是联调局的  他们一直
The F.B.I. They've been wanting
想要染指血腥约翰案
to get their hands on the Red John case for a while.
国土安全局接手的时候他们很不高兴
They were not happy when Homeland Security took over.
对
True.
我一直怀疑联调局里有人在监视我
You know, I've always suspected the F.B.I. are watching me.
私下里
Personally.
虽然听起来很像是太多疑了
As paranoid as it sounds,
但这倒是解释了他们是如何拿到马克思案子的
it would explain how they got the Marx case.
但他们为什么要拷问他
But why would they do this to him?
我们该怎么着手
And how do we proceed?
我不能就直接去联调局问他们
I can't just go to the F.B.I. and ask them
是不是他们杀了马克思
if they killed Marx.
如果联调局在监视我
If the F.B.I. Has been watching me,
我打赌一定是加调局的某位高层
I'll bet that someone very high up in the CBI
批准了此事  至少同意此事
authorized it, or at least went along with it.
我得找他们谈谈
I need to talk to them.
伯特仑  但显然你不能问他
Bertram. But you obviously can't ask him.
那就找玛德琳·海托华
Madeleine Hightower then.
海托华
Hightower?
她已经不在加调局当事三年了
She hasn't run the CBI in three years.
你觉得她还能获得什么信息
What kind of information do you think she still has access to?
就算她能  为什么她愿意跟你分享
And if so, why would she share it with you?
血腥约翰想杀她
Well, Red John tried to kill her.
她肯定会帮我的
She's gonna want to help me.
除非她认为此事错在你
Unless she blames you.
我还是打给她吧
Eh. I'm gonna call her.
好吧
Fine.
你今天打算做些什么
Oh. What do you have planned for the day?
你没什么正式的案子要办  对吧
You don't officially have a case, do you?
就放松下吧
You can relax.
去按摩一下  做个美甲
Get a massage, mani/pedi.
不要
No.
我要去找你名单上的六个人
I have to go and offer protection
向他们提供保护  而你  要给我那六个人的名字
to the six people on your list, which you are going to give me.
我原本还盼着你去做按摩呢
I was hoping you'd opt for the massage.
真不敢相信
Oh, I can't believe it.
终于把他哄睡着了
Finally got him back to sleep.
干得好  瑞斯比先生
Good job, Mr. Rigsby.
接下来的一小时我们也不用出门工作
And we don't have to leave for work for another hour.
我们怎么来打发时间呢
What are we gonna do to pass the time?
还不知道呢  瑞斯比夫人
Well, I don't know, Mrs. Rigsby.
不要啊
Oh... don't.
是里斯本
It's Lisbon.
让她等一会吧
She can wait 10 minutes.
里斯本
Lisbon.
肯定有重要的事  快接吧
It must be important. You should get it.
早啊  头儿
Morning, boss.
你和瑞斯比负责这四个
You and Rigsby take these four.
我负责海尔巴和李
I'll take Haibach and Lee.
海尔巴不是那个圣华金河杀手案里的吗
Isn't Haibach the guy from the Panzer case
拍了很多小女孩照片那个
with all the photos of the little girls?
是的  我之前跟他打过交道
Yeah. I've dealt with him once before,
所以他可能愿意跟我谈
so maybe he'll be more likely to come with me.
强奸指控  贩毒指控
Rape charges, drug charges,
贩卖人口指控
human trafficking charges.
没搞错吧  我们要帮助这些人
Really? We're gonna help these guys?
这就是我们的工作  我们无权选择
That's the job. We don't get to pick and choose.
我们要警告这些人他们现在有生命危险
We need to warn these men that their lives are in danger
并为他们提供保护
and offer them protection.
赶紧开工吧
Now get on it.
今天早晨我一直在看她刷牙
And I was watching her brush her teeth this morning,
她竟然刷了整整两分钟
and she does the full two minutes,
完全按照牙医要求的那样
just like the dentist says.
要是换了别人  我早就觉得烦了
The wrong person, that could be really annoying,
但是今天  我觉得这样挺好
but today I just thought, cool.
我这下半辈子都有她
I'm gonna be spending the rest of my life
-这副好牙相伴  明白吗  -不明白
- with those really good teeth, you know? - Nope.
我的意思是  结婚比我想像得要好
M-my point is, marriage is even better than I thought.
除了
Except...
也不是什么大事  结婚才三天嘛
It's not a big deal. It's only been three days.
也挺有意思的  真的
It's sort of funny, really.
我  我们还没那个过
W-we haven't done it yet.
结婚以后
As a married couple.
酒店那晚呢
What about at the hotel?
婚礼后  我送你们上了马车
After the wedding. I got you that carriage.
是的  我们当时都不省人事了
Yeah, we passed out.
那天太激动了
It was a very emotionally draining day.
-再加上我们喝了很多酒  -也是
- Plus we drank too much. - Right.
而且第二天我们还要工作
Then we had to work the next day.
而且那之后  萨拉一直在洛杉矶开会
And since then, Sara's at a conference in L.A.,
本就一直从早到晚由我们带着
so we've had Ben every day, morning and night.
我在网上看过一篇研究报告
You know, I read a study on the Internet.
上面说女人一旦结婚之后
It said women lose interest in sex
就会马上变得性冷淡
almost immediately after marriage.
达尔文主义者的观点
It's Darwinian.
格蕾斯绝不可能  她总是非常...
Nah, not Grace. She's always been super into...
我的意思是  我不信  不可能是真的
M-my point is, I don't believe it. It's not true.
我只是跟你说我在网上看到的论点
I'm just telling you what the Internet said.
里克·多特  加调局的  开门
Rick Dort? CBI. Open up.
在网上谁想说什么都行
Anyone can say anything on the Internet.
不一定是真的
Doesn't mean it's true.
什么事
Yeah?
多特先生吗
Mr. Dort?
我们是加调局的瑞斯比和周探员
Agents Rigsby and Cho from the CBI.
我们想跟你谈谈
We want to talk to you about--
举起手来  否则打爆你的头
Hands in the air, or I'll shoot you in the head.
伙计  别开枪
Hey, man, don't shoot.
我们有理由相信你有生命危险
We have reason to believe your life's in danger.
我们是来给你提供警方保护的
We came to offer police protection.
什么
What?
你现在有生命危险
Your life is in danger.
是这事
It is?
你们不是因为冰毒  别的事
You're not here about the meth... other thing?
冰[别]的事
The meh... other thing?
没什么别的事
There is no other thing.
口误了
Slip of the tongue.
赶紧出来
Get out of the pool.
格蕾斯  你有点憔悴
Hey, Grace. You look a little peaked.
我知道你为什么一直
I found out why you haven't been able
联系不上海托华了
to get in touch with Hightower.
为什么  告诉我
What is it? Tell me.
我跟她姑姑通过电话  她说
I spoke to her aunt, and she said
海托华和孩子们出事了
Hightower and the kids had an accident.
他们都死了
They're dead.
什么  什么时候的事
What? When?
两周前在墨西哥度假的时候
Two weeks ago on vacation in Mexico.
他们淹死了
They drowned.
为什么我们之前不知道
How come we didn't hear about it sooner?
很奇怪
It's very strange.
他们一直没有找到尸体
Apparently, they never found the bodies,
当局已经停止了搜救工作
and authorities have called off the search and rescue.
你刚才说她姑姑叫什么
Wh-what did you say her aunt's name was?
露比  露比·海托华
Ruby. Ruby hightower.
我需要她的地址
Yeah, well, I-I'gonna need an address.
我得送点花去
I need to send her some flowers.
太不幸了
That's terrible.
我是鲍勃·柯克兰
This is Bob Kirkland.
柯克兰  我是联调局的里德·史密斯探员
Kirkland. This is Agent Reede Smith, F.B.I.
有什么要帮忙的吗  史密斯
What can I do for you, Smith?
我想是你需要我帮忙
I think it's what I can do for you.
我的上级让我把正在查的
My superiors asked that I fill you in
一个案子的详情告诉你
on a case I'm working.
跟派翠克·简有关
It involves Patrick Jane.
说吧
I'm listening.
是一起谋杀绑架案
It's a murder/kidnapping thing.
死者名叫本杰明·马克思
Vic's a guy named Benjamin Marx.
简之前跟他打过交道
Jane dealt with him before.
用了一些  该怎么说呢
Used some... shall we say,
比较过分的方法让他认罪了
over-the-top techniques to get Marx to confess?
听起来像是简会做的事
That sounds about right.
马克思当时在受审  可能会被无罪释放
Marx was on trial, could have gone free.
坦白说  我觉得可能是简干的
Frankly, I like Jane for it.
他跟血腥约翰有过节
He's got a vigilante beef with Red John.
可能这案子跟他有关
Maybe this is his thing.
我觉得你猜得没错
I think you might be on to something.
-干得好  -谢谢
- Nice work. - Thanks.
还有  史密斯  有消息通知我
And, Smith? Keep me in the loop.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
什么事
Yes?
海托华女士
Mrs. Hightower?
节哀顺变
I'm so sorry for your loss.
我以前跟你侄女玛德琳共事过
I used to work with your niece Madeleine,
我希望能跟您谈谈
and, uh, well, I was hoping that maybe we could talk.
这是给您的
These are for you.
快请进
Oh, please come in.
谢谢你  花很漂亮
Thank you. They are very nice.
你最后一次见到你侄女是什么时候
When was the last time you saw your niece?
几周之前  他们去度假之前
A few weeks ago, right before they went on vacation.
她们特意过来看我
They made a point to come and see me.
至少我有机会能跟她们告别
At least I got a chance to say good-bye.
是啊  真是这样
Yeah, well, there-- there's that.
怎么了
What is it?
只是
Oh, it's just, uh...
我真希望我能有什么办法
I just wish that there was some way I could...
让她知道我的感受
let her know how I feel.
可以的
There is.
我的邻居电脑技术很厉害
My neighbor is very good with the computer.
他在网上建了一个
He set up a private memorial site
私人追悼网站
on the Internet
只给朋友和家人悼念用
Just for friends and family.
我想看看
I'd love to see that.
好了  就是这个
Okay, here you go.
你能不能
Oh, d-do you mind?
我不太会用电脑
I'm not very good with computers.
当然  想说什么就说什么
Sure. Just say what you need to say.
这么写
Write this.
死后
In death...
你会获得新生
you have found new life...
我想站在山顶高喊
And I want to shout it from the mountaintops.
纪念玛德琳
我内心深知
I know in my heart,
我最亲爱的玛德琳
dearest Madeleine...
当夕阳落下时
that when sunset comes,
你会在天堂的花园里
I will find you waiting for me...
等着我
in the heavenly gardens.
爱你的  派翠克
Love, Patrick.
说得太
Oh... that was, um...
太感人了
that's lovely.
很有诗意
Very poetical.
谢谢  我感觉好多了
Thank you. Feels a lot better.
我该走了
I should--I should go.
小可怜
Or, you poor lamb.
你有点喜欢她  是吧
You were a little sweet on her, weren't you?
加州  萨克拉门托市  理查德·海尔巴家
不行
No.
我记得你  跟我律师谈去
I remember you. Talk to my lawyer.
海尔巴先生
Mr. Haibach.
不是你想的那样  先听我说完
It's not what you think. Just hear me out.
我想的是  你一直想给我安上个什么罪名
I think you've wanted to pin something on me for a long time.
我不是那么好欺负的  里斯本女士
I won't be your patsy, Ms. Lisbon.
是里斯本探员
It's Agent Lisbon.
我们有理由相信你有生命危险
And we have reason to believe that your life is in danger.
我来这是向你提供警方保护的
I am here to offer you police protection.
这么说如果我跟你走
So if I go with you,
不会有什么倒霉事了
nothing bad will happen to me?
听着像是你们警察的老把戏了  里斯本探员
Sounds like police state trickery, Agent Lisbon.
斯塔西会以你们为荣的
The STASI would be proud.
前东德国家安全部
从法律和道义上讲我都应该通知你
I am legally and morally bound to inform you that--
别在这装什么道德高尚了
Please don't try to stake out the moral high ground here.
如果听你的  我早就因为
If you had your way, I'd be in jail
莫须有的罪而蹲监狱了
for a crime I didn't commit.
这次还是听我的吧
I think I'll take my chances.
怎么样  简
How's it going, Jane?
我刚拜访了海托华的姑姑
I just visited with Hightower's aunt.
太让人伤心了
That's so sad.
有查出什么东西吗
Did you find anything out?
你觉得血腥约翰与此有关吗
I mean, do you think Red John had anything to do with it?
我觉得没有  和他的犯罪手法不一样
I don't think so. Not his M.O.
你觉得只是一场意外吗
So you think it's just an accident?
看起来是的  找人找的怎么样了
Looks like it. How's the roundup going?
海尔巴不愿意跟我走  我觉得他有所隐瞒
Haibach wouldn't come with me. I think he's hiding something.
他那样的人一般都会对女警
Well, a guy like that probably takes issue
有意见
with lady police.
应该说是对女性有意见
Ladies in general.
你说得对  我让周和瑞斯比走一趟
Uh, you're right. You know what? I'll send Cho and Rigsby.
也可以不用
Or not.
他出事也不会有人在意的
Would the world really miss him if something happened?
这就是你我的不同之处
And that's the difference between you and me.
先挂了
And good-bye.
如果你也是加调局的  我要
If you are from CBI, I'm--
怎么回事
What happened?
我们来的时候门开着
We found the door open,
地上有血迹和啤酒瓶
blood and beer bottle on the floor.
海尔巴不见了  瑞斯比正在和邻居问话
No Haibach. Rigsby's canvassing the neighbors.
这可糟了
This is bad.
未必
Not really.
这证实了有人正通过我的名单
Confirms the theory that someone is going through my list
寻找血腥约翰的猜想
trying to find Red John.
海尔巴被绑架了
Haibach has been abducted,
很有可能会被折磨致死
and he's probably gonna be tortured to death.
是啊  他今天晚上会挺难熬的
Yeah, he's in for a rough night.
我们得告诉史密斯和联调局
And we have to tell Smith and the F.B.I.
他被绑架了  还有此案和马克思案有关
that he's been taken and that it's connected to the Marx case.
-不行  不能说  -我们不能说谎
- No, we don't. - We can't lie.
我们一直在说谎
We do it all the time.
他总会理出头绪的
He's gonna put it together eventually,
到时候结果只会更糟
and it'll be worse.
好吧  那就告诉他
Okay, fine. Tell him.
但是不要提名单的事
But do not mention the list.
就告诉他和一桩旧案有关的人失踪了
Just tell him that someone else connected to an old case of ours has gone missing.
我同意
Agreed.
现在该怎么办
What do we do now?
很快就知道了
I will have the answer for that very soon.
黑咖  奶咖
I have black, milk...
以及一杯加奶加糖的
and milk and sugar.
你不喝的我喝
I'll take whatever you don't want.
你总是这么细心吗
You always this thorough?
我喜欢考虑周全
I like to cover all my bases.
加奶加糖的那杯
Milk and sugar.
谢谢
Thanks.
你说你有东西要给我
So you said you got something for me?
我之前跟你说的那个案子
There's been an interesting development
有了点有趣的进展
in that case I was telling you about.
又有一个和简有关的人
Looks like another man's gone missing
失踪了
that's connected with Jane.
一个叫理查德·海尔巴的
A, uh, Richard Haibach.
确实很有趣
That is interesting.
谢谢
Thank you.
虽然这跟我无关  但是
Look, it's none of my business, but, uh...
你和简之间到底什么情况
can I ask what the deal is with you and Jane?
说来话长
Long story.
那随便吧
Whatever.
我也不是要打听什么
I'm not looking to pry.
这点很好
I like that.
我调查了你一下
I've done some research on you.
我吗
On me?
没错  你作为探员很不错
Yeah. You're a good agent.
非常坦白  正直
Real straight shooter.
你为什么要查我
Why would you research me?
我有其他事想跟你谈谈
I have some other business I want to discuss with you.
需要谨慎对待的事
Delicate business.
好  说吧
Okay. Shoot.
老虎  老虎
Tiger tiger.
啥
Huh?
老虎  老虎
Tiger tiger.
你在耍我吗
What, are you messing with me?
那是什么东西  老虎  老虎
What--what is that? "Tiger tiger"?
你真不知道吗
You really don't know?
知道什么
Know what?
没什么  这是个测试
Nothing. That's a test.
好吧
Okay.
我完全一头雾水  你想给我讲讲吗
I'm totally in the dark here. You want to fill me in?
调查血腥约翰的时候
While investigating Red John,
国土安全局开始怀疑
Homeland Security's begun to suspect
在加州执法部门里存在着一个
the existence of a powerful secret organization
强大的秘密组织
within California law enforcement.
警方  加调局  司法部
Police, CBI, D.O.J.
我们认为都是高层人物
Strictly high-level, we think.
他们是干什么的
What do they do?
脏活
They do dirt.
他们互相掩护
They protect each other with major cover-ups,
逃脱谋杀嫌疑
get away with murder.
那老虎又是什么
What's the tiger thing?
我们觉得那是暗号
We think that's the password.
真诡异
Spooky.
血腥约翰是其中一员吗
Is Red John a member?
现在还不好说
It's too soon to tell.
那简呢
What about Jane?
我们只是刚理出头绪
We're just starting to put this thing together.
我们想在联调局里找人合作
We're looking for partners within the F.B.I.
级别较低的
Lower level guys that...
我们确定可以相信的人
we're sure we can trust.
也就是我了
That's me.
乐意效劳
Happy to help.
谢谢
Thank you.
保持联络
I'll be in touch.
谢谢你的咖啡
Thanks for the coffee.
你好  派翠克
Hello, Patrick.
玛德琳
Madeleine.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
喝茶吗
Tea?
好的  谢谢
Yes, please.
把话先说清楚
Just so we're clear,
桌子下面有把枪
I have a gun pointed under the table.
正对着某个重要的东西
And it's pointed at something important.
知道了
Fair enough.
孩子们怎么样了
How are the kids?
她们很安全
They're safe.
你只需要知道这些就行了
That's all you need to know.
你姑姑很不错
Your aunt is a delight.
演技很好
Wonderful actress.
我必须要保护好我和孩子们
I had to do what was best for me and my kids.
我知道劳拉蕾·马丁斯死之后
I knew that Red John was cleaning house
血腥约翰就一直在杀人灭口
after Lorelei Martins was killed.
我可不想成为下一个
I did not want to be next.
我懂的
No, I got it.
他已经试过一次要杀你了
He's already tried to kill you once.
很难从这种事中恢复过来
It's not something you ever really get over.
那到底什么事这么重要
So what's so damn important
你要把我叫出来
you had to bring me out of hiding?
我快要抓住血腥约翰了
I'm getting close to catching Red John,
我需要你的帮助
and I need your help.
我不会为了帮你而置家人于危险之中
I'm not putting my family in danger to help you.
而且我已经离开执法部门三年了
Besides, I've been out of law enforcement for three years.
我怎么帮你  我什么都不知道
How can I help you? I don't know anything.
真的吗
Really?
我知道有件事  你已经隐瞒
Because I think you've been holding something back
很久了
for a very long time.
没错
Yeah, there it is.
我说对了
I'm right.
联调局
The F.B.I.--
一直在监视我  是吗
They've been watching me, haven't they?
如果不重要我不会来的
Please, I wouldn't be here if it weren't important.
告诉我
Tell me.
现在也没理由不告诉你了
Well, I guess there's no reason not to tell you now.
但是你绝对不能说是我告诉你的
But obviously you did not hear this from me.
米内利掌管加调局的时候
When Minnelli was chief of the CBI,
他和联调局局长舒尔茨达成了个协议
he struck a deal with F.B.I. Director Schultz.
舒尔茨想要什么
What did Schultz want?
她要报告
She wanted reports.
你的报告
On you.
米内利给他们了
Minnelli provided them.
米内利退休之后  这事就由我接手了
When Minnelli retired, that became a part of my job.
但是那些情报并不是给联调局的
But the intel wasn't exactly going to the F.B.I.
我发现舒尔茨把情报转交给
I found out that Schultz was passing it on
国土安全局了
to Homeland Security.
-是鲍勃·柯克兰吗  -是的
- Bob Kirkland? - Yes.
为什么
Why?
他觉得你就是血腥约翰
He thought you were Red John.
当然会如此
Of course.
国土安全局监视我多久了
How long have Homeland Security been watching me?
八  九年吧
Eight, nine years.
我当时做了我觉得正确的事
I did what I thought was best at the time.
别指望我会道歉
Don't expect me to apologize.
不  我不会要你道歉
No, no, I-I won't.
简
Jane.
你不能告诉别人你见过我  即使是里斯本
You cannot tell anyone you saw me. Even Lisbon.
我不会的
And I won't.
我说到做到
I meant what I said.
我会杀了血腥约翰
I'm gonna kill Red John,
你就可以恢复正常生活了
and you're gonna get your life back.
希望如此
I hope so.
下一步怎么办
So what's next?
我去见见鲍勃·柯克兰
Well, I'm gonna go see Bob Kirkland.
我要开诚布公地
What I'm looking for is an open
和你谈谈
and honest dialogue.
毫无隐瞒
100% transparency.
我不知道你想从我这里得到什么
I don't know what you want from me.
我没做过什么坏事
I didn't do anything wrong.
也许是还没做
Maybe not yet.
但是看看你的那个地下室
But... that room in your basement.
得了吧
Come on.
你是个堕落的人
You are a depraved man.
最起码是个恋童癖
At minimum, a pedophile.
不过说实话  这不是我们来这的原因
But frankly, that's not why we're here.
那是为了什么
Why then?
求求你告诉我  为什么
Please just tell me... why.
我把你带来是想问几个问题
I brought you here to ask you some questions.
什么都行  我什么都告诉你
Anything. I'll--I'll tell you anything.
那好吧  跟我说说
All right then. Tell me--
你认识我么  以前见过我吗
Do you recognize me? Have you seen me before?
没  我想没有
No... I don't think so.
好的  这问题一会再说  下个问题
Okay, we'll come back to that. Next question.
什么
What?
是什么
你是血腥约翰吗
Are you Red John?
什么
What?
你是  血腥约翰吗
Are you... Red John?
不
No...
你是不是血腥约翰
Are you Red John?!
不是
No!
国土安全部  萨克拉门托地区办
柯克兰探员
Agent Kirkland?
简  你来做什么
Jane, what are you doing here?
能跟你说句话吗
Can I have a quick word?
不是什么私密事  你朋友可以一起
It's nothing private. Your friends can stay.
我等下过去
I'll catch up, guys.
我有一个尚未成型的推论
I have a pet theory
希望你能帮我确认或否决一下
I was hoping you could confirm or deny.
看我能力吧
I'll see what I can do.
国土安全局是不是一直在调查我
Has Homeland Security been investigating me?
是的
Yes.
你居然可以正面回答我
I'm surprised you're allowed to tell me that.
你们通常不都是喜欢保密吗
I mean, you guys are usually so cloak and dagger.
国土安全局在调查血腥约翰的案子
Well, it's no secret that Homeland Security
已经不再是秘密
has the Red John case.
而你的名字以各种方式出现在了其中
Yeah, your name has come up in various ways.
是啊  那你们的人有没有闯入我的办公室
Right. So then did you guys break into my office
偷走了疑犯名单
and steal my list of suspects?
当然没有
Absolutely not.
没有  为什么
No? Why not?
因为我们不在乎你认为谁是血腥约翰
Because we don't care who you think Red John is.
这案子归我们管
We have the case.
明白了
Point taken.
谢谢你抽出时间
Thanks for your time.
就这些
That's it?
是啊  我只是想确保
Yeah. I just wanted to make sure
你们不是在做无用功
you weren't on a wild goose chase,
因为不管是谁闯进了我的办公室
because whoever it was that broke into my office,
他们偷走了假的疑犯名单
they stole a fake list of suspects.
做得好
Well played.
谢谢  我也这么觉得
Thank you. I thought so.
也许你该来为我们工作
Maybe you should come work for us.
还是算了吧
Maybe not.
需要我载你一程吗
You need a ride somewhere?
我自己走就行  谢谢
No, I'm--I'm good, thanks.
我们应该多谈谈  上车吧
Well, we should talk some more. Get in the car.
我有得选吗
Do I have a choice?
没有
No.
那好吧
By all means...
我们再多谈谈吧
Let's talk some more.
让我看看你的手机
Let me see your phone.
你不需要这样  我就是想和你谈谈
Hey, you don't have to do this. I actually want to talk to you.
把手机给我
Just hand me the phone.
请系好安全带
Seatbelt, please.
你们有没有简的消息
Hey, have you guys heard from Jane?
没有
Nope.
昨天早上之后就没见过他了
I haven't seen him since yesterday morning.
给他打电话都转到了语音信箱
His phone just keeps on going straight to voicemail.
你能帮我定一下位吗
Can you ping it for me?
可以啊  就是得花点时间
Sure. It'll take me a little while.
谢了  也可能什么事都没有
Thanks. It's probably nothing.
就是这里了
And here we are.
继续走
Keep moving.
我喜欢你对这地方做的改造
Oh, I love what you've done with the place.
来吧  我领你简单参观一下
Come on, I'll give you the 10-cent tour.
求你  救救我
Help me... please.
这位是理查德·海尔巴  这位是派翠克·简
Richard Haibach, Patrick Jane.
救我
Help me.
我就是想让你看看把你带入
I just wanted you to see the face of the man
这场麻烦的男人的脸
who got you into this mess.
其实这事挺有趣的
It's a funny story, actually--
一场错误造成的闹剧
a comedy of errors.
求求你放了我吧
Please let me go.
-不  -求你
--No. - Please.
但是别担心  简也有得受了
But don't worry. Jane'll get his, too.
那么  让我们来谈谈真正的
So, let's talk about that real list
血腥约翰案疑犯名单吧
of Red John suspects.
我定位不到简手机的位置
I couldn't get a hit on Jane's phone.
不管他在哪  那里都没有手机信号
Wherever he is, he has no cell service.
可能是他打来的
That's probably him now.
我是里斯本
This is Lisbon.
你好  里斯本  知道我是谁吗
Hello, Lisbon. Do you know who this is?
知道
Yes.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我昨天见了简
I met with Jane yesterday.
他没提起过
He didn't say.
我叫他不要告诉你的
I asked him not to tell you,
但是我觉得我让他陷入麻烦了
but I think I might have gotten him into trouble.
我给他打了一天的电话
I've been trying to call him all day.
我也是
Me, too.
我昨天给了他一些线索
I gave him some information yesterday.
他有没有说要去见谁
Did he say anything to you about who he was going to see?
没有  他该说吗
No. Should he have?
是的
Yes.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
因为我  简可能做了一件
I think I might have caused Jane
非常蠢的事情
to do something very dumb.
名单这事还真有意思
Funny thing about the list.
不过  我不想告诉你
I'd... rather not share it with you.
我明白
I get it.
这一直是你个人最在意的案子
It's been your pet project for a long time.
但我也一样
Mine, too.
你一定会和我分享的
But you will share it with me.
要不我给你一个名字作为开头
What if I just give you one name to start?
罗伯特·柯克兰
Robert Kirkland.
有意思
Interesting.
挺有道理的倒是
Makes sense, actually.
但完全对我没有帮助  对吧
But it doesn't really help me with my cause, though, does it?
应该没有  我看错你了
No, I suppose not. I was wrong about you.
你不是血腥约翰  你和我一样在追捕他
You're not Red John. You're hunting him, same as me.
也不太一样
Not exactly the same.
只要能完成这件事  我可以不惜杀七个人
I'm willing to kill seven people to get the job done.
令人印象深刻啊[法语]
Touché.
你为什么不呢
Why aren't you?
因为那样我就会成为杀人犯
Cause that would make me a murderer.
你还准备杀了血腥约翰呢
You're planning on murdering Red John.
你这说法都是冲突的
That doesn't make any sense.
好吧  我们俩有不同的处理方式
Okay, so we--we both have different approaches,
但重要的是  我们有一个相同的目标
but the important thing here is that we share a common goal.
我们可以一起合作帮助对方
We can help each other if we work together.
我对合作没有什么兴趣
I'm not interested in working together,
并且我认为你也没有
and I doubt you are, either.
我们都想要报仇
We both want our revenge,
但只有一个人可以如愿以偿
and only one of us is going to get it.
罗伯特·柯克兰
Robert Kirkland.
我知道我应该感到惊讶  可是
I know I should be surprised, but--
但他本就挺可怕的  就这么回事
But he's a creepy guy, that's why.
他会带简去哪
Where would he take Jane?
可能就去他带本杰明·马克思去的地方
Probably the same place he took Benjamin Marx.
简在马克思的鞋里发现了松树针
Jane saw a pine needle in Marx's shoe.
好像在他被杀之前
It was like he'd walked through a pine forest
曾穿过一片松树林
before he was killed.
加州北部有一大片松树林
Lots of pine needles in Northern California.
柯克兰每天都要上班
Kirkland would be keeping up appearances.
每天都要到办公室  所以
He'd be going to the office every day, so...
会在萨克拉门托百英里内的松林里吗
Pine forest within a hundred-mile radius of Sacramento?
有可能  就目前来看只能这么推断了
Sure, sure. If that's all we got.
头儿
Hey, boss.
范佩尔  我需要你帮我查点东西
Van Pelt, I need you to run something for me.
位于州议会大厦百英里内  所有罗伯特·柯克兰
Properties or businesses owned by Robert Kirkland
名下的地产或公司
within 100 miles of the Capitol...
并且要与松树林相邻
in close proximity to a pine forest.
罗伯特·柯克兰
Robert Kirkland?
说来话长
It's a long story.
百英里内没有罗伯特·柯克兰名下的地产
Nothing for Robert Kirkland within a hundred miles.
倒是有个叫迈克尔·柯克兰的
But there's a Michael Kirkland.
在埃尔多拉多州立公园附近有个小木屋
Owns a cabin up near El Dorado State Park.
迈克尔是他亲戚吗
Oh, is he a relative?
我不知道  可以查查看
I don't know. I can check.
好吧  把地址发我
All right, text me the address.
好的
Sure.
我们应该请求当地部门支援
We should call local authorities for backup.
不不  别叫警察
No. No. No cops.
不能让人知道我的存在  拜托了
Nobody can know about me. Please.
好吧
Okay.
那我们要怎么办
How do we do this?
就这么办
That's how.
你有兄弟姐妹吗  简
Do you have siblings, Jane?
没有
No.
我有个双胞胎兄弟  迈克尔
I had a twin brother-- Michael.
我们一起长大  亲密无间
We were very close growing up.
我听说双胞胎之间坚固的纽带
I hear that's a strong bond.
我爸是个有施虐狂的醉鬼
And our father was a sadistic drunk.
他常把我们和我母亲打得家都不认识
He beat the crap out of us and our mother.
最后把她打得实在受不了了
Beat her till she couldn't take it anymore.
-她走了  -用剃须刀片把自己了结了
- She left? - With a razor blade.
从那以后
After that,
就只剩我和迈克尔了
it was just me and Michael.
他只能事事仰仗着我
I was all he had.
你比较坚强
You were the stronger one.
是的
Yeah.
后来我长大了  离开了家
Uh, I grew up. I got away.
可是迈克尔不行
But Michael couldn't do it.
他留在了家里
He stayed at home
眼看着我爸喝酒丧了命
and watched our father drink himself to death.
可是有其父  必有其子
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
你说对了
You're right.
迈克尔也开始酗酒
Michael turned to the bottle,
好像他必须以酒为生
drank like his life depended on it.
我付钱让他去治疗
I paid for treatments.
带他参加戒酒互助会
I took him to meetings.
毫无效果
Nothing worked.
然后呢
Until?
有一天他遇见了某个人
Until one day he met someone,
那个人可以拯救他
a man who could help him.
何止是某个人  简直是救世主
More than a man. A savior.
对  就是血腥约翰
Yeah. Red John.
他要的回报不多
He only asked for a few simple things in return.
忠诚和牺牲
Devotion and sacrifice.
迈克尔越陷越深
Michael drifted further and further away
直到有一天他不知所踪了
until one day he was gone.
我再也没有见过他
I never saw him again.
你认为血腥约翰把你兄弟杀了
You think Red John killed your brother.
没错
Yes.
我一直没找到他
I never found him,
但我心里清楚
but in my heart, I know.
看我胡扯些什么呢
Look at me blab.
你又不是我的心理医生
I-I... you're not my therapist.
我不是带你来这儿聊天的
I didn't bring you here to talk.
请告诉我嫌犯都有谁
Please tell me who the suspects are.
不行
No.
随你便
Have it your way.
你知道我会拷问你的吧
You understand, I'm gonna have to torture you.
你不像是能承受肉体痛苦的人
You don't seem like someone who deals well with physical pain.
不怎么行
Uh, not particularly.
那就给我个名字
A name then.
不行
I can't do it.
好吧
Fine.
天呐
God!
好  好  好
Okay, okay, okay.
你必须明白
You... you--you have to understand,
从感情角度上出发
this is hard for me...
这对我很艰难
emotionally.
我还从没跟任何人透露过这几个人的名字
I've never said any of these names out loud to anyone.
给我个名字
A name.
尚海沃
Turtmee.
名为布瑶
First name--Don.
布瑶·尚海沃
Don Turtmee?
不要伤害我
"Don't hurt me."
受不了你
You got me.
那个  我可得...
Why, I oughta...
把手举起来
Put your hands in the air!
把手举到我们能看得到的地方
Keep 'em where we can see 'em!
简  你没事吧
Jane, you all right?
再好没有了
Oh, never better.
我没事  好得很
I'm just fine. Dandy.
还好我们来了
Ooh! Thanks to us.
你竟然傻到一个人来
You were foolish to come here alone.
其实你很开心吧
You taking pleasure in this?
别误会了
Don't get me wrong.
你就是个惹事儿精
You are a pain in the ass.
谢了
Well, thank you.
不过我不希望你出事
But I wouldn't want anything bad to happen to you,
尤其当事出于我的时候
especially when it would be my fault.
现在你肯定觉得问心无愧了吧
Well, I'm sure your conscience is clear now.
没错  所以别来烦我了
It is. Now leave me alone.
下次你再找我
Next time I hear from you,
最好是告诉我血腥约翰已经死了
you better be telling me Red John is dead.
说好了
Deal.
一言为定
That is a deal.
谢谢你  玛德琳
Thank you, Madeleine.
不客气  派翠克
You're welcome, Patrick.
祝你好运
Good luck.
里斯本
Lisbon...
-你自己没问题吧  -是的
- You good here? - Yeah.
现在可以请求支援了
You can call for that backup now.
我会找你算账的
You'll pay for this!
我不会饶了你的  这事儿都怪你
I won't forget! This is on you!
你真的没事吗
You sure you're all right?
名单上缩短到五个人了
The list is down to five names.
这就更好查了
That is a very manageable number.
我怎么就没这感觉
Somehow that doesn't reassure me.
到了最后时刻了  里斯本
We're in the home stretch, Lisbon.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
那个
So, uh,
看来我误会你了
looks like I got it wrong about you.
是啊  你是误会他了
Yeah. Looks like you did.
没事  孰能无过呢
Ah, it's all right. We all make mistakes.
我说
I mean, a...
竟然会是国土安全部的探员
a homeland security agent?
真是想不到  是吧
Who would have thought, right?
不包括我
Not me.
剩下就是一堆管辖权的麻烦事儿了
It's gonna be a jurisdictional cluster-bomb.
不过我们会先把他扣留在县里
But we'll book him first at county.
过几天再把他转押到
In a few days he'll get transferred
联邦看守所
to a federal detention center.
-我想和他聊几句  -没问题
- I'd like to talk to him for a sec. - Sure.
简
Hey, Jane.
既往不咎了吧
No hard feelings, huh?
当然了  既往不咎
No. No hard feelings.
里斯本
Lisbon.
你要是还有话要说
If you have anything else to say,
最好现在就说
now would be the time.
我掌握了点东西
Oh, I might know some things.
不过现在说不合适
But this isn't the best place to talk.
到时候来见我
Come see me sometime.
会的
I will.
你会坚持到底吧
Are you gonna finish this thing?
会的
Yes.
里斯本来电话了
Hey. Lisbon called.
他们今晚不回局里了
They're not coming back into the office tonight.
-知道了  -你也可以走了
- Okay. - You can probably go, too.
-其他人都走了  -是啊
- There's nobody else here. - Sure.
你换衣服了
Did you change?
你说这件旧衣服吗
What, this old thing?
等等  这是什么
Wait. What's this?
像是酒店房卡
It looks like a hotel room key.
等一下  你不会是
Wait. You didn't, did you?
是的  订了蜜月套房
I did. The honeymoon suite.
卡佩罗夫人在照看本
Mrs. Capello is watching Ben.
太棒了  谢谢
That's amazing. Thank you.
我都开始以为...
You know, I was beginning to think--
我知道你怎么想的
I know what you thought.
我是不是疯了
And am I crazy?
是的
Yes.
别想太多了  韦恩
You shouldn't think so much, Wayne.
走吧
Come on.
当我不存在
Don't mind me.
我和他谈谈
Let me speak to him.
怎么了  你怎么来了
What's going on? What are you doing here?
其实你的分析非常正确  鲍勃
You hit the nail on the head, Bob.
关于什么
About what?
执法部门内部确实存在一个强大的组织
There is a powerful organization within law enforcement.
不过比你以为的更大
But it's a lot bigger than you thought.
不光是高层参与了
It's not just the big boys, either.
像我这种级别低的也可以进
They even let lower level guys like me in.
我知道你什么意思了
I know what you're doing.
我们已经盯你很久了
We've had our eye on you for a long time.
我们不过想帮个忙  仅此而已
We just want to help. It's what we do.
怎么帮
Help me how?
仔细听好了
Listen to me closely.
这是个安全屋的地址
That's the address of a safe house.
从这儿往正东两英里
It's 2 miles due east of here.
你到了那儿  会有人接应你
When you get there, someone will contact you,
给你钱  新的身份  还有衣服
Get you some money, I.D., clothes.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
快  鲍勃
Come on, Bob.
下车
Get out of the van.
跑吧
Start running.
就在这儿动手吧
Just do it here.
我更希望你跑
Actually, I'd prefer it if you ran.
你知道的  规矩是这样
You know... protocol.
柯克兰探员意图逃跑
Agent Kirkland tried to escape.
你别无他法  只能将其击毙
You had no choice but to use deadly force.
明白了吗
Do you understand?
老虎老虎
Tiger tiger.